Koray Kurtoglu

Austin, TX - (954)-544 7554

Gmail LinkedIn GitHub Portfolio Website

I'm resilient and disciplined in staying focused on completing my goals until my desired outcome is met, and I love going above and beyond that. I'm also a career driven person and I have a "lifetime learning" mindset. Based on my previous work experiences, I believe that I'm a good team player, hardworking, positive and fully motivated person. Every role that I take in the company, I would love to add international perspectives and useful ideas on top of my role to make the job easier and effective.

Skills

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, ReactJS, NodeJS, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, SQL, GitHub, Django, APIs.

Experience

Software Engineering Immersive

General Assembly | Washington, D.C. | December 2021-March 2022

Successfully completed 500+ hours of expert-led applied computer science fundamentals using the industry's most in demand technologies. Learned Front-end and Back-end languages including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, Express, Python and Django and SQL database.

- Developed projects, including a game called "CARD OF WAR" using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- LavenWoods Alchemy (Developed within a group of 4 people)
- Node.js, Express, MangoDB and Mongoose. It's also a full CRUD project with a RESTful layout.
- SportForLife-ReactJS, bootstrap, API technology, Express, Heroku for deployment.
- RightAway-Python, Django and SQL database.

Penske Logistics

Route Driver/Driver Mentor | Grand Prairie, TX | September 2019-October 2021.

Worked a year as a route driver and started mentoring new drivers and showing them how the work needs to be done if the company trainer needs to work on something else that could not be able to work that day.

- Follow appropriate safety procedures while driving trucks to the Penske location or customer locations.
- Deliver the products to the Starbucks locations in a certain period of time.

- Check vehicles to ensure that mechanical, safety, and emergency equipment is in good working order, report to location manager if any issues are found
- Obtain receipts or signatures for delivered goods and collect payment for services when required.
- Report vehicle defects, accidents, traffic violations, or damage to the vehicles.

Liquid Environmental Solution

Tanker Driver | Dallas, TX | August 2018-September 2019

Collecting disposable liquid with a company tanker and vacuum operator, from different locations.I was responsible for complying with all DOT, state regulations, and company safety and compliance policies.

Labatt Food Service

Truck Driver | Dallas, TX | July 2017-June 2018

I worked as a route driver, delivering the company products to the customers at different locations.

- Follow appropriate safety procedures while driving trucks to the Penske location or customer locations.
- Deliver the products to Schools, local restaurants and organizations in a certain period of time.
- Obtain receipts or signatures for delivered goods and collect payment for services when required.

Four Seasons |

Pool Bar Supervisor | Miami, FL | June 2016-July 2017

I started this role as a waiter and took this position as it became available. After the supervisor position, there was more responsibility added to my waiter position. I would work as a waiter and top of that, I would make schedules for the other team members and cover their shifts as needed.

- Open up the pool bar and make sure everything is in the right place.
- Check the items that we were selling and do inventory checks daily and weekly.
- Divide the sections for the other team members and show their responsible areas for that day.
- Solve and report any problems or any unexpected situation that happens that day.

Pelican Grand Beach Resort

Front Desk S Supervisor | Fort Lauderdale, FL | June 2015-June 2016

I took this position right after I graduated from my university. Since I had previous experience for many years, they sponsored me, made a contract for a year. I got a trainee for 3 months for this role and started my shift supervisor role right after that.

- Leadership and support to all front office personnel and ensures proper completion of all front office duties in accordance with hotel policies and procedures.
- Maintain a professional and high quality service oriented environment at all times.
- Dealing with complaints, problem solving, disturbances, special requests and any other issues that may arise.
- Works with the team to forecast and manage rates to maximize revenue for the hotel.
- Directs staff that performs the following duties and will also perform these duties on its own: welcomes and registers hotel guests, explaining the accommodations and establishing credit or method of payment.

Education

General Assembly

Software Engineering Immersive | Full Stack Web Developer | Austin, Tx | September 2021-March 2022

Udemy And Free Code Camp Online Classes | Full Stack Web Development | Online | August 2021 - March 2022

Akdeniz University | Business And Hotel Management | Turkey | June 2011 – June 2015